Dheerajjha

Sr Backend Developer



Personal Detail

Dheeraj@thedijje.com +918826-810-280 Thedijje.com

Hard skills

PHP Codeigniter

LAMP AWS UX

REST GIT SQL

BASH PWA React

Laravel Docker JS

Soft skills

Leadership

Communication

Project management

Analytical skills

Conferences

LaravelLive india
PyCon india
ng-India

Eye-sparkling experience in small to big project mostly single handedly, full stack developer with passion for coding, solving real world problem through code & system desgin while keeping business and cost in mind. Believe in thinking twice and code once. Leading LaravelDelhi community, part of PyDelhi, Pycon and LaravelLive.

Experience

2017 - Current

CTE International private limited

- * Tech lead, handled product and team since inception of idea
- * Handled system design, project development, server infrastructure and cost management.
- * Team consist of Backend, iOS, Android developer and front-end developers

2015 - 2017

Winculum services/Incisiv.io

- * Transformed entire multi-site Wordpress based research tool to single app.
- * Created 10+ tools for customer interaction to leverage research and ROI of business.
- * Worked more than ever as team despite of being remote work culture.

2015 - 2015

Netmaxims Solution/Technologies

- * Boosted project development by introducing and transforming projects from core PHP to Codeigniter framework.
- * Removed hassle of Wordpress by creating developer friendly CMS in CI thus moving forward small project by 3x.
- * Managed projects on Opencart, Wordpress, Woocommerce.

Education

2010-2014

B.Tech in CS from KU - Kurukshetra

- * Followed passion and changed branch to CS
- * Spend well time in blogging, learning basic programming.
- * Made our college's official site with CMS.
- * Create various micro-sites for college events management and increase student's participation in extra curricular activities.

Achievements

- * Zonal winner of NNSC and top 10 in national level
- * Blog with 2.5M+ hits
- * Talk at various conferences/Meetups
- * Volunteering for Pycon, LaravelLive, PyDelhi, LaravelLive Delhi.